A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Business Interests, Series C FA312
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Companies
  - Companies - International Harvester Company, 1944-1954 (Box 40, Folder 357)
    Miscellaneous material. Fowler McCormick's resignation. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John P. Wilson.
    62.2In
  - Companies - National Broadcasting Company, 1939-1959 (Box 41, Folder 358)
    Invitations to programs; early description of television. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    62.2Na
  - Companies - Pakistan Industrial Credit and Investment Corporation, 1957-1960 (Box 41, Folder 359)
    Organizing of corporation to provide loans and investment capital to Pakistanians. David Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller 3rd investment; descriptions of loans; organization problems, relation with governments. Effects of 1958 military coup. Robert Weber's resignation. Relation with Economic Development Corporation and International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) via Weber. Correspondents include Robert Weber, David Rockefeller, R. W. Purcell.
    62.2P3
  - Companies - Radio Corporation of America, 1932-1955 (Box 41, Folder 360)
    Bertram Cutler on Board; remained on Board after Rockefellers disposed of their shares. Company activities. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler, David Sarnoff.
    62.2R2
  - Companies - State of Israel Bonds, 1951-1958 (Box 41, Folder 361)
    Appeals to purchase bonds declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    62.2S7
  - Companies - Toy Furniture Shop, 1922-1941 (Box 41, Folder 362)
    Friends of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. owned Providence toy factory, asked Abby Aldrich Rockefeller to invest; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. investigated and invested $3,000. Financial troubles; additional John D. Rockefeller, Jr. aid; bankruptcy, reorganization. Attempt to establish tie with Williamsburg. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frank Staley, Charles O. Heydt.
    62.2T6
  - Companies - Western Union Telegraph Company, 1907-1955 (Box 41, Folder 363)
    Courtesies extended to John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. by company. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel.
    62.2W31
  - Companies - Western Union Telegraph Company - 1918 Strike (Box 41, Folder 364)
  - Companies - Mountain Fuel Supply Company, 1928-1952 (Box 41, Folder 365)
    John D. Rockefeller invested in natural gas company through Ohio Oil Company; no management interest. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Bertram Cutler.
    62.2W5
  - Companies - Witherbee Sherman Corporation, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 366)
    Information on corporation collected by Laurance S. Rockefeller; no action.
    62.2W8
- Everett Timber and Investment Company
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company, 1892-1895 (Box 42, Folder 367)
    Organized by H. Hewitt, Jr., G. S. Brown, Walter Oakes, 1891; John D. Rockefeller represented on Board by Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, Cary, Greene; by 1916, John D. Rockefeller owned most of stock. Sold timberland to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1922. Tax problems; land management; 1934 decision to sell all British Columbia lands. Sale of Washington lands by 1940. Correspondents include F. H. Brownell, Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt.
    117
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company, 1895 (Box 42, Folder 0367A)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company, 1896-1898 (Box 42, Folder 368)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company, 1914-1933 (Box 42, Folder 369)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company, 1934-1956 (Box 42, Folder 370)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - 1928 Sale to Canadian Western Lumber Company (Box 42, Folder 371)
    For $200,000.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - F. A. Steuert, 1922-1925 (Box 42, Folder 372)
    Unsuccessful attempt to get John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to increase his lumber holdings.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Statements re Property, 1922-1938 (Box 42, Folder 373)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s profits.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Canadian Western Lumber Company, 1935-1937 (Box 42, Folder 374)
    Details of sale for $375,000.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Abstracts, Deeds, etc., 1890-1892 (Box 43, Folder 375)
    Title to lands purchased by company; copies of original agreements between John D. Rockefeller, James Colgate, Henry Jewitt and Colgate Hoyt; abstracts of land titles.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Abstracts, Deeds, etc., 1893-1894 (Box 43, Folder 376)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Abstracts, Deeds, etc., 1894-1895 (Box 43, Folder 377)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Abstracts, Deeds, etc., 1895-1898 (Box 43, Folder 378)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Abstracts, Deeds, etc., 1898-1899 (Box 43, Folder 379)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Abstracts, Deeds, etc., 1900-1907 (Box 43, Folder 380)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Abstracts, Deeds, etc. (Box 44, Folder 381)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Alberni Pacific Company, 1934-1936 (Box 44, Folder 382)
    Details for sale of half John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s timber land investments to Alberni. Correspondents include F. H. Brownell, B. P. Turnbull, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Legal Papers, 1906-1922 (Box 44, Folder 383)
    Copies of deeds and land titles in British Columbia and Washington.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Everett Timberlands - Maps (Box 44, Folder 384)
    Maps of land holdings in British Columbia and Washington.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Taxes, 1936-1939 (Box 45, Folder 385)
    Summary of real estate taxes paid 1922-1936; British Columbia claim for income tax on sales of land, 1934-1936, adjusted and settled by nominal payment. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, J. Lawson, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Tucker Cruise, 1935-1945 (Box 45, Folder 386)
    Employment of cruiser to keep check on lands; watched Alberni operations; reports. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull, J. E. Tucker, H. F. Brownell.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Sale to Alberni Pacific Company, 1936-1938 (Box 45, Folder 387)
    Arrangement of terms for 1936 land sale; fulfillment of contract. Protection of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interests while time payments being made. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, B. P. Turnbull, H. R. MacMillan.
    117A
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Sale to Alberni Pacific Company, 1939-1953 (Box 45, Folder 0387A)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Sale to Victoria Lumber Company, 1936 (Box 45, Folder 388)
    Sale of land for $450,000 cash to Weyerhaeuser group. Correspondents include H. P. Brownell, J. Humbird.
    117B
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Sale of Nanaimo and Comax Tracts, 1936-1939 (Box 45, Folder 389)
    Sale details; time payment arrangement; account paid up in 1939. Correspondents include James H. Lawson, F. H. Brownell, B. P. Turnbull, J. Humbird.
    117C
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Sale of Jump River Tract to Victoria Lumber Company, 1936-1940 (Box 45, Folder 390)
    $600,000 purchase paid off in 1936 with 1 1/2 discount on balance. Correspondents include J. Humbird, B. P. Turnbull, F. H. Brownell.
    117D
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Gailbraith Timber Company, 1940-1944 (Box 45, Folder 391)
    Sale of timber to contract-logging firm - some sold outright, some on a contract basis. Paid for as cut. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull, Thomas M. Debevoise, H. F. Brownell.
    117E
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Whatcom County Tract, 1936-1942 (Box 45, Folder 392)
    Efforts to sell Washington timber; sold at a loss in 1942. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull.
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Whatcom County Tract - McCormick Lumber Company, 1936-1942 (Box 45, Folder 0392A)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Whatcom County Tract - Sale to RM Rounds, 1936-1942 (Box 45, Folder 0392B)
  - Everett Timber and Investment Company - Whatcom County Tract - Weyerhaeuser Timber Company, 1936-1942 (Box 45, Folder 0392C)
- Fairway Farms Corporation
  - Fairway Farms Corporation, 1924-1942 (Box 46, Folder 393)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. loan to Montana group for experimental work connected with Montana university; develop new approach to farm ownership through loan of working capital to tenants. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. lent $125,000; operations crippled by bad weather, depression: business deal became a philanthropy; unpaid notes given to Farm Foundation. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
    206
  - Fairway Farms Corporation, 1926-1940 (Box 46, Folder 394)
  - Farm Foundation - Fairway Farms, 1933-1950 (Box 46, Folder 395)
    Loan of $150,000 to Fairway Farms turned over to Foundation for research on rural life; notes assigned to Foundation. Report on work. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
- Filatures et Tissages Africains
  - Filatures et Tissages Africains, 1945-1948 (Box 46, Folder 396)
    Establishment of cotton textile mill in Belgian Congo; survey of conditions; equipping mill. Laurance S. Rockefeller and Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. shared investment with Belgian group; company's progress. Correspondents include Joseph Jenner, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    242
  - Filatures et Tissages Africains, 1949-1961 (Box 46, Folder 397)
  - Filatures et Tissages Africains - Minutes, 1946-1959 (Box 46, Folder 398)
    Copies of minutes of Board of Directors and stockholders meetings.
    242M
  - Filatures et Tissages Africains - Board of Directors Meetings - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Box 46, Folder 399)
    242S
  - Filatures et Tissages Africains - Stock Purchase, 1946-1958 (Box 46, Folder 400)
    Division of stock holdings among brothers after partnership company dissolved. Purchases of additional stock. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Abby Rockefeller Mauz.
    DR material removed to Folder 400A.
  - Filatures et Tissages Africains - Stock Purchase, 1946-1958 (Box 46, Folder 0400A)
  - Filatures et Tissages Africains - Sale of Stock, 1947-1949 (Box 46, Folder 401)
    Some Rockefeller stock sold to other American investors.
- International Business Machines, Inc. (IBM)
  - International Business Machines, 1938-1961 (Box 46, Folder 402)
    Friendship between T. J. Watson and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Request for articles for "Think." Invitations to dinners. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    221
    DR material removed to Folder 402A.
  - International Business Machines, 1938-1961 (Box 46, Folder 0402A)
    Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
- Insurance
  - Insurance - Merchants Fire Assurance Association, 1907-1923 (Box 47, Folder 403)
    E. L. Ballard invited John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to invest in company; $200,000 invested, 1909. Rockefellers held half of stock; Bertram Cutler guided company's investment policies. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. L. Ballard, Bertram Cutler.
    151
  - Insurance - Merchants Fire Assurance Association, 1924-1960 (Box 47, Folder 404)
  - Insurance - Merchants Fire Assurance Association - Invitation to Join Board of Directors, 1914 (Box 47, Folder 405)
  - Insurance - Merchants Fire Assurance Association - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1938-1952 (Box 47, Folder 406)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller's interest in corporation; reports on examination by New York State Department of Insurance. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Insurance - Merchants Fire Assurance Association - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1938-1953 (Box 47, Folder 407)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller elected director to replace John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on board; information on company operations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Bertram Cutler.
    151L
  - Insurance - Merchants Fire Assurance Association - Laurance S. Rockefeller - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Resignation, 1937 (Box 47, Folder 408)
    Exchange of directors stock between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Insurance - Workmen's Compensation Insurance, 1935-1959 (Box 48, Folder 409)
    Employee coverage; compensation paid. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel.
    151.1
  - Insurance - Life Insurance - Annuities, 1932-1959 (Box 48, Folder 410)
    Suggestion that family take out life insurance - declined. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Robert W. Gumbel.
    151.2
  - Insurance - Life Insurance - R. H. Mackey, 1932-1935 (Box 48, Folder 411)
    Attempts to sell Nelson A. Rockefeller life insurance.
  - Insurance - Life Insurance - Insurance for Negroes, 1932-1933 (Box 48, Folder 412)
    Attempts to interest John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in Negro insurance company.
  - Insurance - Life Insurance - Policy Holders Protective Association, 1944-1954 (Box 48, Folder 413)
    A lobbying group; no Rockefeller interest.
  - Insurance - Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States, 1936-1961 (Box 48, Folder 414)
    Offers of insurance policies; all declined. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel.
    151.3
  - Insurance - Washington Assurance Corporation, 1924-1937 (Box 48, Folder 415)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Laurance S. Rockefeller served as corporation directors for auxiliary of Merchants Fire Assurance Corporation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Bertram Cutler.
    151.4
  - Insurance - New York Life Insurance Company, 1949-1961 (Box 48, Folder 416)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd became director, 1949; analysis of company policies. Letters of congratulation. John D. Rockefeller 3rd resigned in 1959. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, R. H. Mansfield, D. C. Josephs.
    151.6
  - Insurance - New York Life Insurance Company - Mr. Rockefeller's 3rd Address, January 1956 (Box 48, Folder 0416A)
- Marion Fruit Company
  - Marion Fruit Company, 1890-1936 (Box 48, Folder 417)
    Summary letter on Idlewild Fruit Company, 1911; summary memo on Florida fruit companies. 1890 investment in Florida orange grove wiped out by frost, 1894-1895; slow rebuilding; 1925 sale.
    118
- Marston and Company
  - Marston and Company, 1957-1964 (Box 49, Folder 418)
    Partnership formed in office to hold oil company securities owned by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. so as to relieve John D. Rockefeller, Jr. from necessity of signing security transfers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler, John E. Lockwood.
    41
  - Marston and Company - Holdings, 1957-1959 (Box 49, Folder 419)
  - Marston and Company - Financial Material, 1957-1961 (Box 49, Folder 420)
  - Marston and Company - Financial Material - Bank Statements, 1957-1960 (Box 49, Folder 421)
- Minnesota Iron Mines
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Franklin Iron Mines, June-September 1883 (Box 49, Folder 422)
    Frank Rockefeller and James Corrigan's investment in Messabi Range. Franklin Mines purchased first by Corrigan; then F. Rockefeller investment. John D. Rockefeller financed to $124,000, plus additional short-term working capital; John D. Rockefeller held most of stock, 1893-1899, as collateral for loans. Several attempts by Frank Rockefeller to sell Franklin Iron Mines to John D. Rockefeller and Frederick T. Gates as part of Lake Superior Consolidated Iron Mine Company. John D. Rockefeller represented throughout by Frederick T. Gates; Frederick T. Gates also supervised ore railroad and selling of ore in 1898. 1898, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. agent for John D. Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick T. Gates, Frank Rockefeller, James corrigan, M. A. Hanna, C. W. Rogers, H. W. Oliver.
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Franklin Iron Mines, September-December 1883 (Box 49, Folder 423)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Franklin Iron Mines, January-April 1884 (Box 49, Folder 424)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Franklin Iron Mines, April-August 1884 (Box 49, Folder 425)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Franklin Iron Mines, September 1884-May 1885 (Box 49, Folder 426)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Franklin Iron Mines, May 1885-December 1887 (Box 49, Folder 427)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Franklin Iron Mines, 1899 (Box 50, Folder 429)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Franklin Iron Mines, 1898 (Box 50, Folder 428)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Penokee and Gogebic Consolidated Mines (Box 50, Folder 430)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Tilden Mining Company - Lease to Oliver Mining Company, 1891-1896 (Box 50, Folder 431)
    Oliver, Frederick T. Gates and John D. Rockefeller jockey for position vis a vis exploitation of John D. Rockefeller's iron lands; establishment of tie with A. Carnegie. Rockefeller companies: Lake Superior Consolidated Iron Mines, Duluth, Missabi and Northern Railroad, and Bessemer Steamship Company. John D. Rockefeller owned Tilden, a lessee from Keweenaw Associates; then sublet to Oliver, 1899-1914. Routine after 1898; exhaustion of natural resources. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, H. W. Oliver, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Tilden Mining Company - Lease to Oliver Mining Company, 1897-1898 (Box 50, Folder 432)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Tilden Mining Company - Lease to Oliver Mining Company, 1899-1911 (Box 50, Folder 433)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Tilden Mining Company, 1911-1927 (Box 51, Folder 434)
    Routine administrative correspondence by company officers. Majority of stock owned by United States Steel and Rockefeller Foundation. Company practically inoperative - leased land from fee holders and directly sublet it to Oliver Iron Company. Sales of land and timber. 1927-1928, Oliver Company cancels its lease; search for new lessee; reduction of stock. Problems of mineral exhaustion. Negotiations for land. Foundation sale of stock, 1942. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, E. V. Cary, Charles Scheide, L. G. Myers, A. L. Boulware, Thomas M. Debevoise, Leferts Dashiel, Charles O. Heydt, C. P. Fish.
    48
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Tilden Mining Company, 1927-1942 (Box 51, Folder 435)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy
    John D. Rockefeller investments in Minnesota Iron Company. Loan to L. Merritt through C. W. Wetmore for Duluth, Missabi and Northern Railroad. Lake Superior Consolidated Mines Company. L. Merritt debts; John D. Rockefeller loans; Penokee and Geobic failure. 1893 suits in Duluth's "populist" jury, decisions against John D. Rockefeller; appeal, reversal. 1911 Stanley investigation; Frederick T. Gates' defense of John D. Rockefeller's 1893 actions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, C. W. Wetmore, L. Merritt, G. W. Murray, H. R. Rogers, A. A. Harris.
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, 1892-1893 (Box 51, Folder 436)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, July 1893 (Box 51, Folder 437)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, September 1893 (Box 51, Folder 438)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, September-November 1893 (Box 52, Folder 439)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, December 1893-January 1894 (Box 52, Folder 440)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, February-April 1894 (Box 52, Folder 441)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, May-December 1894 (Box 52, Folder 442)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, January-April 1895 (Box 52, Folder 443)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, May-June 1895 (Box 52, Folder 444)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, July-August 1895 (Box 53, Folder 445)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, September-December 1895 (Box 53, Folder 446)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, January 1896-June 1897 (Box 53, Folder 447)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, July 1897-August 1898 (Box 53, Folder 448)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, July 1899-February 1912 (Box 53, Folder 449)
    - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy, March 1912-October 1950 (Box 53, Folder 450)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Work Papers Used in Duluth Suit - Frederick T. Gates, 1893-1894 (Box 54, Folder 451)
    Settlement of stock ownership question: statements and summaries re loans, collateral, stock ownership. Frederick T. Gates dictations, record of his movements. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates.
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Working Papers Used in Duluth Suit - Re Stock Ownership (Box 54, Folder 452)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Working Papers Used in Duluth Suit - Re Stock Ownership (Box 54, Folder 453)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Working Papers Used in Duluth Suit - Re Loans and Collateral (Box 54, Folder 454)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Working Papers Used in Duluth Suit - Telegrams (Box 54, Folder 455)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Working Papers Used in Duluth Suit - Frederick T. Gates Dictations and Notes (Box 54, Folder 456)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Legal Papers and Contracts, 1893-1896 (Box 55, Folder 457)
    Certified copies and originals; contracts of agreement in consolidation, power of attorney. Dismissal of charges against John D. Rockefeller; statement by Merritts.
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Literary Bureau, 1895-1896 (Box 55, Folder 458)
    Frederick T. Gates employs H. P. Hall to secure newspaper space to present John D. Rockefeller's side of case before appeal hearing; Hall's activities. Price paid for placement of stories; exposure of Hall's activities. Correspondents include H. P. Hall, Frederick T. Gates, John D. Rockefeller.
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Newspaper Clippings - Publicity, 1893-1896 (Box 55, Folder 459)
    Lake Superior Consolidated Iron Mines and Missabi Range; Merritt Controversy. Stories placed by Hall in various northwestern newspapers.
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Stanley Investigation, 1911-1912 (Box 55, Folder 460)
    Transcript of Congressional hearing; newspaper comment. Manuscript of Frederick T. Gates' article on John D. Rockefeller and the Merritts.
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Cash Value of Merritt Mines and Stocks, 1912 (Box 55, Folder 461)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Court Records, 1894-1897; 10 items (Box 56, Folder 0461A)
    Transcript of Record. United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 8th Circuit, December 1895. John D. Rockefeller vs Merritt. Opinion of Court ibid. Briefs of Defendent ibid. Brief of Plaintiff in Error. Several copies of each.
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Court Records, 1894-1897 (Box 57, Folder 0461B)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Frederick T. Gates Pamphlet - "The Truth About Mr. Rockefeller and the Merritts" (Box 58, Folder 0461C)
    80 copies of Frederick T. Gates' undated pamphlet.
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Merritt Controversy - Newspaper Clippings, 1895 (Box 59, Folder 462)
  - Minnesota Iron Mines - Frank Rockefeller - Personal and Ranch, 1881-1894 (Box 59, Folder 463)